Not all Technical Safety Requirements are
并非所有技术安全要求
derived directly from Software Safety Requirements.
都可以从软件安全要求直接导出
There are actually five other categories of
实际上 根据 ISO 26262 的要求
Technical Safety Requirements that ISO 26262 requires.
还有5类其他的技术安全要求
Two of the categories are for detecting false either within
其中的两个类别 一是系统失效检测
the system or in an external device interacting with the system.
二是与系统交互的外部设备失效检测
The other three categories are from
另外三类包括
measures that enable the system to reach a safe state,
1、能够让系统达到安全状态的措施
to implement a warning and degradation concept,
2、实现一个报警和降格的概念
or to prevent latent faults.
3、预防潜在的失效
Here is an example of each case for the lane departure warning function.
这里是一个车道偏离报警功能的例子 可以用来说明上述各类情况
A fault within a system could either be
系统内故障可能包括软件错误
a software error or a hardware component that malfunctions.
以及硬件组件失灵
A general technical safety requirement would be that the validity and
一个通用的技术安全要求是 应确保数据传输的正确性和完整性
integrity of the data transmission for the LDW_Torque_Request signal shall be ensured.
在这里 数据指的是与车道偏离警告相关的扭矩请求信号
We will talk about specific methods for checking
在视频下方的文本中 我们会讲述
data validity and integrity in the text below the video.
检测数据有效性和完整性的详细方法
Now, let's look at a fault that is external to the Lane Assistance Item.
现在 我们来看一个故障 这个故障对于车道辅助模块而言是外部的
Let's say hypothetically, an external anti-lock brake
我们假设一个外部的防抱死制动 ECU
ECU was transmitting speed information to the Lane Keeping Assistance Item.
正在向车道保持辅助设备传输速度信息
An error in the communication line between
在制动 ECU 和 转向助力 ECU 之间的一个传输错误
the brake ECU and the power steering ECU could cause a failure.
可能导致一个故障发生
Code needs to be added that checks for
需要添加一些代码 来检测
communication errors and the information gets transmitted between ECUs.
ECU 之间的通讯故障 并获取相关信息
We will derive a technical safety requirement that
这样 我们就可以推出一个技术安全要求
enables the system to reach and maintain a safe state.
该要求让系统更可以达到并维持安全状态
We already derived the safe state in the functional safety concept.
在功能安全概念中 我们已经得出安全状态
The Lane Assistance System shall be switched off.
那就是 车道辅助系统应该被关闭
A technical safety requirement would be that,
对应的技术安全要求则是
as soon as a failure is detected by the LDW function,
一旦 LDW 功能检测到一个故障
it shall deactivate the LDW feature and the LDW_Torque_Request shall be set to zero.
应该马上使 LDW 的功能失效 并把 LDW 模块的扭矩请求值置为0
The next category involves
技术安全要求的下一个类别是
Technical Safety Requirements for implementing warning and degradation concepts.
实现报警和降格概念
We have already said in the previous lesson that a warning light
在上一课中 我们讲过
will turn on if the Lane Assistance Item malfunctions.
如果车道辅助模块失灵 报警灯会亮起来
A technical safety requirement would be that,
对应的技术安全要求则是
as soon as the LDW function deactivates the LDW feature,
一旦 LDW 功能使 LDW 模块失效时
the LDW safety software block shall send
LDW 安全软件模块应马上发信号到车辆的显示系统 ECU
a signal to the car display ECU to turn on a warning light.
该信号会打开报警灯
And finally, let's discuss an example of measure that prevents latent faults.
最后 我们来讨论一个与预防潜在失效措施相关的例子
Latent faults are errors that exist but can not be detected.
潜在错误是指已存在但是未能检测到的错误
An example would be a software error in the code that actually checks for the failures.
一个例子是用来检测故障的软件代码中的错误
Measures against latent faults generally take place during power up,
预防潜在故障的措施通常发生在
power down, or during maintenance.
加电 断电 或者维护过程中
A Technical Safety Requirement for the Lane Keeping Assistance would be;
对于车道保持辅助模块来说 对应的技术安全要求是
memory test shall be conducted at the start up
在 EPS ECU 启动时进行内存检测
of EPS ECU to check for any faults in memory.
检测内存是否有故障
The functional safety standard only requires avoiding latent faults for items labeled
功能安全标准只要求避免 ASIL C 或 D 级别模块的潜在故障
ASIL C or D. Now that we have described different types of Technical Safety Requirements,
现在 我们已经讨论了不同类型的技术安全要求
we are going to discuss adding attributes to these requirements.
接下来 我们会讨论与这些要求相关的一些其他属性
Attributes include ASIL, Fault Tolerant Time Intervals,
包括 ASIL 容错时间间隔
and a description of Safe State Transition.
以及对于安全状态转换的描述